now you're really cooking
you've got more than gusto
you've got goals
a power system
magical remedies
and a smooth ride through MV
but the quest book has you spooked
things are getting more complicated quickly
chemical lines
multi step automation
new mods and metals
and brand new circuit components you've never seen
what in the world
gregtech
that's what
welcome back to the beginners guide to GregTech New Horizons
today we upgrade
if you're waiting to take things to the next level
you're in the right place
this is episode 7
MV
there's not a ton of preamble this time
you should have a goal for your power system
and maybe some goodies you already know you want to grab
and you're probably already feeling the power spike
you can't run your EBF full time
make that a goal
and don't be afraid to use multiple types of power production to make it happen
and keep the aluminum cranking
by using the alumina and cryolite recipe
and don't forget steel
as usual, "you're gonna hate this" quest unlock the meat of the chapter
and let that be your reminder to get familiar with conveyors and pumps
the chemical lines you'll be diving into in MV
are gonna require cell management for fluids
and you're probably at the point where upgrading the covers on your power system makes sense for transport speed
the flawless emerald for the sensor might be a bit of a trick
but enough poking around the nether should get you a few
or you can look into sifting
for the most part, MV is about upgrades
either for speed, bonus output or cost
after you get the extruder for more efficient rod production
the next thing on the list is probably the electrolyzer
you actually can make it right away
without getting that "you're gonna hate this" quest
but the extruder will help you keep scaling towards your power plan
so it's probably six one way, half dozen the other
you need it all either way
speaking of, there's some crossover dependencies inside the MV chapter
but you can approach it with different paths
this is just one
and to be fair to the electrolyzer
it's probably the most important machine of the tier
to start you'll probably just be slamming different dust through the machine
and routing the outputs to drawers
that'll work just fine to begin
just make sure you have enough drawers for all the outputs
and you're storing all the fluid outputs
and have a way to avoid water
you'll need to electrolyze ruby dust for chrome
find one with redstone ore veins and a lot of it
electrolyzing sodalite is great for starting silicon and sodium
and stockpiling aluminum dust
and salt is ideal for chlorine
but that hardened clay biome you found ages ago
is about to become critically important
even if only for a short while
macerate it, then electrolyze the clay dust
for tons of aluminum, sodium, lithium and silicon dioxide
the silicon dioxide can be sent through a chemical reactor with magnesium
which you can get by centrifuging marble dust
to get raw silicon dust
this is 100 percent going to be worth automating end to end
the magnesium can be recycled, also in an electrolyzer
to get the original magnesium back
so the only input item is the silicon dioxide dust
the magnesium input is what's called a closed loop
meaning the same system that produces your ideal output
also produces more of your input items
you want to look for these as often as you can
there are many other ways to get silicon dioxide too
most players are going to want glass
so a little setup to turn cobblestone into glass dust
some being turned into glass
and some into silicon dioxide
will make it renewable
another thing you'll want to be looking for as often as you can
and you plug it into the same setup you're using for clay dust
there are several use cases for raw silicon
but for now the most important one is silicon solar grade dust
there are two paths to making it
and both have closed loop input items
making raw silicon dust the only input
the tetrachloride route is a little bit easier for cell management
but it does take an extra machine to get the chlorine back
the trichlorethylene route doesn't have any extra byproduct recycling
but only deals with fluids
so cell management can be tricky
either way
start working towards a full drawer of the stuff
and be ready for a lot more
while your SSG stacks up it's time to pivot to plastics
polyethylene is one that has a ton of uses early
from cheaper circuit components to EnderIO conduits and many more
just like there are new circuits in every tier
there are new plastics too
they're usually not required right away
and polyethylene is no different
you can get the HV circuits at the end of the chapter without it
and the circuit boards the quest line calls out aren't actually needed until HV
but not having it would make the next part a lot more expensive
if you didn't notice during the LV tier
there are a couple different types of circuit components that can work to make each circuit
the recipe will rotate through them
so you can see everything that works
there are also multiple ways to make each component
each with a higher return in exchange for a better material
TLDR: make the best thing you can afford, always
staying in supply of tantalum at this point probably isn't realistic
or possible at all
and as the quest book suggests
the resistor is probably the only upgrade you can afford right now
but they're worth it
even with the electrum recipe
you can also view the entire circuitry with this little button
there's a lot here
and honestly
this is most useful for illustrating two things
the first is the order of upgrades per tier of circuit
along the horizontal
from most to least expensive
or set another way
from the first ones you'll make
to the last ones you'll make
and the other is
which circuit boards are required for which level of circuit
along the vertical
from the lowest tier to the highest tier
it can be a little confusing
so to simplify
in order to advance
you'll need to make preposterously expensive mainframe circuits using cheap boards
and to unlock the cheaper circuit recipes
you'll need to unlock better boards
so, now you know why you don't want to delay your chemistry
it's going to get ridiculously expensive to proceed if you do
the next step is actually doing it
making polyethylene is the easy part
you just mix ethylene with oxygen
you already know how to make oxygen
so if you need more
give polyethylene its own oxygen setup
it's a little early to share fluid setups easily
so if you're having trouble doing it
don't bother
you can take it over too
but if you don't have enough chores with all the mining and ore processing you've been doing
I'd be surprised
surely you haven't forgotten about mining, right?
we'll get back to that
for now, ethylene
like most things there are a number of ways to get it
and the way you choose will probably be connected to your power system choice
at this point
things are getting pretty busy
so if you need to take a beat here
and get organized with your power system
definitely do
check out episode 5 if you missed it for more details on the options
the good news is
your silicone is probably built up enough by now
that you can start thinking about the MV Energy hatch
stock back up on gallium and arsenic
it's still a bit painful
but MV miners are great
and blast furnace your way to some boules
this is a long smelting operation
so make sure you don't run out of fuel
grab the MV cutting machine and Laser Engraver too
the thaumcraft shards you grab for magic can be made into the Tera lenses and Ignis lenses if you struggled for emerald and ruby
but for the RAM you need later
you'll have to hunt down sapphires
for now grab the Terra lens
and make low power ICs and the MV Energy hatch
if you manage to get the other ones too
take advantage of cheaper LV and MV circuits starting right away
feel free to upgrade the EBF now too
but definitely upgrade your power system
the EBF will be relevant soon
but if you're opting for steam or benzene for long term power
what you need at the moment is the pyrolysis oven
get your farms an oven set for power
then divert some wood into a secondary pyrolysis to make wood gas
using circuit 5
and don't forget the nitrogen for efficiency
then distill the wood gas for ethylene
easy peasy
ready to mix with oxygen
if you opted for fuel like I did in my main world
the straightest line to ethylene for now is to divert some of the light fuel into a chemical reactor
mix with steam for severely steamed light fuel
and distill for ethylene
you can complicate this a bit by making lightly steamed light fuel instead
and distilling into naphtha first
then steaming it again
and distilling the naphtha into ethylene for a better return
but if you're going oil long term
it might be better to wait for the distillation tower to do that
even if you got crazy and went bio-diesel for power
there's a way to get ethylene through ethanol and sulfuric acid
but like everything else
it's a big investment that's only worth it if the plans all align for you
you can also get into EnderIO now
we aren't going to cover it here
because the quest book does a great job of walking you through
but I'll say this
item conduits with item filters will be life changing
now, with power well under control
and polyethylene in hand
it's time to get back to the EBF
double up on MV Energy hatches
and get that bad boy to HV
and get ready to roll some coal
you got plenty of chrome by now from all the electrolyzing too
oh you forgot about that
back to the mines with you immediately
anyway mix up some kanthal dust in your new MV mixer
and get to smelting
to cool the hot ingots
you'll need a chemical bath with some coolant in
you make the coolant with water and lapis dust
which means it's effectively free
I might catch some heat for this one
but I don't think it's worth using the tank and fan to recycle the coolant
just make the distilled water
and max out a tank of the stuff
with 128 buckets
you can cool over 500 ingots
which was way more than I personally needed before crafting the vacuum freezer
with the basic cooling system
some kanthal coils
which by the way this time require mica
so if you cheaped out last time, get the prospecting
you can start cooking and cooling SSG ingots
and start making HV circuits at last
the very very expensive way
and finally the HV metal, stainless steel
you're probably hurting for chrome
and that's totally normal
so get back to the mines
or start centrifuging that outrageous backlog of redstone for extra ruby dust
and power the setup using all that mercury and an acid generator
it was exactly at this point in my own journey that
I pivoted into magic and bees to solve for some of these trickier resources
there are other ways to approach getting ruby
and if you're having serious trouble
definitely consider using the ruby juice
the only trick is the hydrochloric acid
but let's not pretend like you have enough ruby to need it infinitely
and anyway, match up as much stainless as you can afford
you'll be making some more multi blocks in the next tier
and they're expensive
and so it was that you were ready for HV
how about that
there are some things we glossed over though
so let's do some highlights
EnderIO has some amazing things to offer
from easy travel around your base
to automated mob spawning and killing
it's different in GTNH, naturally
but still amazing
and the dark steel chests are needed for the compressed chest
godliest of all for purposes of mining
polyvinyl Chloride is a little French for now
but super worth having around as you start making improved circuit components with your polyethylene
and make straight out of pipes
the prospecting tool is a gift from Greg himself
no more digging down to check ore veins
The World Accelerator is an incredibly useful
if equally power hungry little block that speeds up the tick rate of blocks and entities around it
void upgrades keep your automated systems moving
especially power
super chests, for massive storage capacity of single items
transporters, for close range item and fluid transport
so many goodies to enjoy
and one big giant gotcha
since you don't need those circuit boards now
it can be easy to ignore the iron III Chloride or the sodium persulfate
don't overlook this
you need giant quantities
so you either need to think hard about sulfuric acid
or you need to think hard about chlorine
it's not urgent
but once you start needing it during HV
you'll hit a brick wall if you can't make quite a lot
you might have also noticed
there weren't as many single block machine quests this time
get used to that
but don't forget
every tier has new additions of all the machines
and they're all better
other than that
be ready for the big one
new multi blocks, the clean room
the moon
titanium
applied energistics
are you really a beginner anymore
I guess we'll find out in HV
see you there for episode 8
现在你是真的开干了
你不只有干劲
你有目标
电力系统
还有魔法药剂
再加上MV阶段一路顺风
但是任务书吓到你了
事情很快就会变得更复杂
化学线
多步自动化
新的模组和金属
以及你从未见过的全新电路元件
这到底是啥？
格雷格科技
就是它
欢迎回到GregTech New Horizons初学者指南
今天我们升级
如果你想让事情更上一层楼
你来对地方了
这是第7集
MV
这次的开场白不多
你应该为你的动力系统设定一个目标
也许还有一些你已经知道你想拿的好东西
你可能已经感受到用电压力暴涨了
你的EBF还没法全时运行
把它作为一个目标
不要害怕使用多种类型的电力生产来实现它
同时继续稳定量产铝
用氧化铝+冰晶石那条配方线
别忘了钢铁
像往常一样，“你会讨厌这个”的任务解锁了这一章的内容
也提醒你尽快熟悉传送带和泵
你在MV会深入的化工产线
会需要做流体单元管理
你可能正处于升级电力系统覆盖板来提速运输就很有必要的地步
传感器要的无瑕祖母绿可能有点麻烦
不过在下界多逛一逛通常能搞到一些
或者你也可以考虑筛矿
在大多数情况下，MV是关于升级的
无论是速度、额外产出还是成本
获得更高效的棒材生产的挤出机后
名单上的下一件事可能是电解槽
其实你可以立刻就做。
没有得到“你会讨厌这个”的任务
但挤出机会更有助于你继续扩建供电方案
所以两条路都差不多
反正这些机器你都得做
顺带一提，MV章节内部有一些交叉依赖
不过你可以走不同路线推进
这只是一个
为了对电解槽公平起见
这可能是这层最重要的机器
开局你大概率就是把各种粉往机器里塞
并把产物分流到抽屉
这样起步完全够用
只要确保你有足够的抽屉来放所有的输出
你储存了所有的液体输出
并且要有处理水副产物的办法
你需要电解红宝石粉来获得铬
去找红石矿脉并大量开采
电解方钠石很适合前期启动硅和钠
并储存铝粉
盐是氯的理想选择
但是你很久以前发现的硬化黏土生物群系
即将变得至关重要
即使只有很短的一段时间
先粉碎再电解黏土粉
能产出大量铝、钠、锂和二氧化硅
二氧化硅可以和镁一起通过化学反应器
你可以通过离心大理石灰尘来获得
得到粗硅粉
这是100%值得端到端自动化的
镁可以回收，也可以在电解槽中回收
把原来的镁拿回来
所以唯一净输入是二氧化硅粉尘
镁的输入就是所谓的闭环
这意味着产生理想输出的相同系统
还会产生更多的输入材料
你想尽可能经常地寻找这些
还有许多其他方法可以获得二氧化硅
大多数玩家会想要玻璃
所以把圆石打成玻璃粉的小装置
有些被变成了玻璃
一部分再转成二氧化硅
将使其可再生
这也是你应尽量经常寻找的套路
可以直接接进你做黏土粉那套系统
粗硅有不少用途
但目前最重要的是太阳能级硅粉
有两条路可以走
并且都有闭环输入材料
使原始硅粉成为唯一的输入
四氯化硅路线对细胞管理更容易一点
但是需要一台额外的机器才能把氯拿回来
三氯乙烯路线没有任何额外的副产品回收
但只处理液体
所以细胞管理可能很棘手
不管怎样
开始朝着满满一抽屉的东西努力
并为更多做好准备
当你的SSG堆积起来时，是时候转向塑料了
聚乙烯在早期有很多用途。
从更便宜的电路组件到EnderIO导管等等
就像每层都有新电路一样
还有新的塑料
它们通常不会立刻就要用到
聚乙烯也不例外
你可以在没有它的情况下得到本章末尾的高压电路
任务线点名的电路板其实到HV才真正需要
但是没有它会让下一部分更贵。
如果你在LV层没注意到
有几个不同类型的电路组件可以工作，使每个电路
配方会在这些选项间轮换
这样你就可以看到所有有效的东西。
也有多种方法来制作每个组件
每一个都有更高的回报以换取更好的材料
一句话：永远做你当前负担得起的最好方案
在这一点上保持钽的供应可能是不现实的
或者根本不可能
正如任务书所说的
电阻器可能是您现在唯一能负担得起的升级
但它们是值得的
即使是琥珀金配方也值得做
你也可以点这个小按钮查看完整电路树
这里有很多
老实说
这对说明两件事最有用
第一个是每层电路的升级顺序
沿水平方向
从最贵到最便宜
换个说法
从你要做的第一个开始
到你要做的最后一个
另一个是
哪个级别的电路需要哪些电路板
沿垂直方向
从最低层到最高层
这可能有点令人困惑
所以为了简化
为了前进
你得先用便宜板子去做贵得离谱的主电路
并解锁更便宜的电路配方
你需要解锁更好的板子
现在你知道为什么不想耽误化学反应了吧
如果你这样做，继续下去会变得非常昂贵
下一步就是真正去做。
制造聚乙烯是最简单的部分
你只要把乙烯和氧气混合
你已经知道怎么制造氧气了
所以如果你需要更多
给聚乙烯自己的氧气装置
这个阶段还不太适合轻松共用流体系统
所以如果你做这件事有困难
不用麻烦了
你也可以先把这块放一放
但是如果你没有足够的活儿来处理你一直在做的采矿和矿石加工
我会惊讶的
你肯定没有忘记采矿，对吧？
我们回头再说
现在是乙烯
像大多数事情一样，有很多方法可以得到它
您选择的方式可能与您的电力系统选择有关
在这一点上
事情越来越忙了
所以如果你需要在这里休息一下
用你的电力系统组织起来
就这么做
如果您错过了第5集，请查看第5集，了解有关选项的更多详细信息
好消息是
你的硅粉现在大概率已经攒得差不多了
可以开始考虑做MV能源仓了
把镓和砷再补一波库存
还是有点疼
不过MV矿机真的很好用。
然后去高炉慢慢烧出几根晶锭。
这是一个漫长的冶炼作业
所以确保你没有用完燃料
顺手把MV切割机和激光雕刻机也做了
如果你祖母绿和红宝石不够，做魔法时拿到的神秘时代碎片可以做Terra和Ignis镜片
但后面要做RAM的话
你得去找蓝宝石
现在，用地之魔晶透镜就行
并制造低功耗IC和MV能源仓
如果你也把其他几种镜片做出来了
立即开始使用更便宜的LV和MV电路
现在也可以随时升级EBF
但一定要升级你的动力系统
EBF很快就会再次成为重点
但是如果你选择蒸汽或苯作为长期动力
你现在需要的是热解炉
先给农场配一套热解炉发电产线
再分流一部分木头进第二套热解炉来产木炭气
使用编程电路5
别忘了氮气来提高效率
然后把木炭气蒸馏出乙烯
非常简单
准备与氧气混合
如果你像我一样选择柴油发电
目前最直接的路线是将一些轻燃油转移到化学反应釜中
用蒸汽裂化出重度蒸汽裂化轻燃油
然后蒸馏出乙烯
你也可以走轻度蒸汽裂化轻燃油这条更复杂的路线
先蒸馏成石脑油
然后用蒸汽裂化一次
将石脑油蒸馏成乙烯能获得更多产物
但是如果你要长期使用石油
等有了蒸馏塔才这么做可能更好
即使你疯了，用生物柴油发电
可以通过乙醇和硫酸得到乙烯
但就像其他一切一样
这是一项巨大的投资，只有当计划都适合你时才值得
现在你也可以开始发展EnderIO了
这里我们就不展开讲了
因为任务书引导得很好
但我要说
带过滤器的物品导管会彻底改变你的游戏体验
现在，随着电力得到控制
聚乙烯产线正常运转
是时候回到EBF了
装上两个MV能源仓
把这大家升压到HV
然后准备好开卷煤线（？）
你现在也从电解中得到了足够的铬
噢，你把这事忘了是吧
马上回去挖矿吧
总之在新的MV搅拌机里混合出坎塔尔粉
然后开炉冶炼
要给热锭降温
你需要一个加冷却剂的化学浸洗机
你用水和青金石粉做冷却剂
这意味着它基本上是免费的
这句可能会有点争议
但我认为不值得用储罐和散热片来回收冷却液
只有做点蒸馏水
直接做一整罐冷却液
128桶冷却液能冷却500多个锭
（向上合并）
这远超我自己在做出真空冷冻机之前的冷却需求
有了这套基础冷却系统
再做一些坎塔尔线圈
顺便说一下，这次需要云母
所以如果你上次做线圈偷懒了，现在就去探矿
你就能开始烧制与冷却高速钢锭
终于可以开始做HV电路
以非常非常贵的方式做
最后是HV金属：不锈钢
你现在大概率很缺铬
这完全正常
所以回去挖矿吧
或者把那塞满你仓库的红石拿去离心，获得额外的红宝石粉
再用你攒的汞和酸性发电机给整套系统供电
我就是在自己游戏的这个阶段
转去做魔法和蜜蜂，来获取难搞的资源
还有其他方法可以获得红宝石
如果你遇到了严重的麻烦
可以严肃考虑走红宝石汁路线
唯一的麻烦的是盐酸
但也别假装你红宝石自由到能够无限做红宝石汁
总之，在你承受的范围内，多做些不锈钢
下一个阶段你还会做更多的多方块机器
而它们都很贵
所以你已经准备好进入HV了
怎么样，厉害吧
不过有些事情我们忽略了
所以来做个重点回顾
EIO提供了一些惊人的东西
从在基地内快速旅行
到自动刷怪和杀怪
自然地，它在GTNH中是不同的（？）
但还是很牛逼
压缩箱子需要先做玄钢箱子
对采矿来说简直神中神
现在做聚氯乙烯稍微有点早
但当你开始用聚乙烯做改良电路组件时，它会非常值
聚乙烯还能直接拿来做管道
探矿仪是格雷自己送的礼物
再也不用往下挖找矿脉了
世界加速器非常有用
它同样也很耗电，但能加速周围方块和实体的tick速率
虚空升级能让自动化系统持续运转
尤其是电力系统
超级箱，用于存储大量单一物品
转运器，用于近距离物品和流体运输
这么多好东西可以享受
还有一个要避坑的点
既然你现在不需要那些电路基板了
你很容易会忽略三氯化铁和过硫酸钠
不要忽视这一点
这两样你后面会需要海量
所以你要么好好想想怎么做硫酸
要么想想怎么获得氯
这并不紧急
但是一旦你在HV期间开始需要它
一旦产能跟不上，你会被狠狠卡脖子
你可能也注意到了
这次没有那么多单方块机器任务
习惯吧
但别忘了
所有类型的机器在每个电压都有新版本
他们都更好
除此之外
准备迎接大家伙
新的多方块机器：超净间
月球
钛
应用能源
你真的是初学者了吗？
我想我们会在HV阶段见分晓
第8集见